Hello everyone. Welcome back to today's another tutorial topic. So today I am going for the MongoDB
application using the MongoDB shell. So in this session, I'll just try for perfectly explained
how to perform the complex data manipulation and analyzing using for the MongoDB
application framework. So I have perfectly connected for my MongoDB
compass for the shell insert and you can perfectly check this option, then go for the shell inside.
I can click on the data syntax. So here I have perfectly switched for the MongoDB shell
on my database. So here first is the first example. So first of all, I can use the dollar sign
with the matches stage to fill the document. So first of all, here I can create for the DB
dot the students dot use the aggregate function and here I can create for the parenthesis
and use the dollar sign. So you can see here the already defined for this aggregate all the function
and now just go for here just again create for all the data. Okay. So now first of all,
here I can type for the DB, then use the students dot aggregate and here I can create for
the parenthesis, then the square brackets and also here I can create for the curly brackets.
So instead first of all, I'll use this match and get the toner. I can create first of all the
curly brackets in the sensor defined for the edge column. Okay. And also here I can create
for the again the curly brackets, then tag for the dollar sign for the DB function.
And also this parenthesis is 25. Okay. Great. And then and now here simply perfectly type
and this comment will create that document from the collection or the case will is greater than
or equal to 25. So now just press enter and you can see here the all information. This is greater
than 35 at the beginning. Okay. So this is completely working. Next step here, I can use for
the grouping instance. So here I can type for the DB dot students dot use the aggregate
and here first of all, create the parenthesis, then also use the square brackets. Okay.
And now here I can create for the curly brackets. So here first of all, I can create the dollar
sign, then type here, the you can see R or UB group function. Okay. And create here the
full and first of all, I can create the curly brackets. So first of all, I can type the underscore
I took it. Then I can define for the double quotation. Okay. And in this inside, I can create
for the dollar sign, define this C-T column. Okay. And here I can use for the total age. Okay.
So define for the total age and predictions. Can here use for again, the curly brackets,
then use for the dollar sign, the sum operator. And now use for again. So now first of all,
create the double quotation. And in this inside, create for the dollar sign and also
have a point for each product. Okay. So now here we have completely used and this statement.
And it can simply use the permanent group by collection by the C-T field and calculate the total
for each C-T. Okay. So define this perfectly now. And here I can create for this. And you can see
it is perfectly working this command. So total is 256, 50, 40. And total is 18. Okay. So this statement
is perfectly working. Okay. So we can see here perfectly used for this statement and completely
working now. Okay. So there in this session perfectly done and I have perfectly used the MongoDB
aggregation using the MongoDB shell. Okay. So I hope you found this tutorial helpful. So stay tuned
for more tips and tricks for the MongoDB. So thank you for watching and happy coding.